香   港
看看谁终于醒了
Look who's finally awake.
正好赶上你头一回见烟花
Just in time for your first fireworks.
漂亮吗?
Aren't they beautiful?
春   节
就像你一样, 我可爱的小包子
Just like you, my sweet bun.
真奇怪
That's odd.
哦 不 我们被发现了
Oh, no. They found us.
宝贝, 抓好你的宾基
Baby, hang on to your Binky.
奶奶能搞定
Grandma's got this.
Boots with the fur With the fur
看看这傻乎乎的妖怪.
Look at the silly yaoguai.
再见, 多莉
Bye-bye, dolly!
"再见" 是对的
"Bye-bye" is right.
别担心 汤姆 救援马上就到
Don't worry, Tom. Help is on the way.
She turned around
And gave that Big booty a slap
再见了, 笨蛋们!
So long, suckers!
Shawty got low, low Low,
low, low, low, low, low
She had them Apple bottom jeans
Boots with the fur With the fur
The whole club Was lookin' at her
喵, 喵
Meow, meow.
给你 没什么好担心的 看到了吗?
There you go. Nothing to worry about, see?
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
你在哪里?
Where are you?
不好意思 小心点 借过
Excuse me. Watch out. Coming through.
为猪排快车让路!
Make way for the Pork Chop Express!
谁说猪不会飞?
Who says pigs can't fly?
看看是谁终于决定露面了
Look who finally decided to show up.
让开, 山羊
Clear the path, Goat.
我们走 都知道规矩的 生肖们 保护守护者
Let's go. You know the drill, Zodiac. Protect the Guardian.
攻击!
Attack!
吃我一支羽箭, 妖怪＜/i
Eat feathers, yaoguai!
踢啊踢啊踢
Kick and kick and kick.
可爱攻击
Cute attack!
马, 把他们圈起来
Horse, round them up.
哦, 这可不妙
Ooh, that's not good.
李太太
Mrs. Lee!
老虎 不 等等我们
Tiger, no! Wait for us!
SUBTiTLE: DEX𝟕ER
老  虎
的  学  徒
旧  金  山
One two fleeka You wanna pop my speakers
Three, two, three, better
Blow your mama's teeth out
I chew like I'm Pika
Then I spit like I'm Nina
十 五 年 以 后
下次走路小心点, 废物
Watch where you're going next time, loser.
也许你走路才要小心点, 大赢家
Maybe you can watch where you're walking, winner.
我猜你不会
I guess not.
你还好吗?
You okay?
我很好
Yeah, I'm great.
嘿, 你是新来的那女孩
Hey. You're the new girl.
来了有一段时间啦
Been a girl for a while now.
我是汤姆 好的 我马上回来
I'm Tom. Okay, I'll be right back.
你死定了
You are so dead.
怎么个死法, 比如, 百分百死翘翘?
Not just mostly dead, but actually, like, a hundred percent dead?
随他去吧
He's not worth it, man.
逃跑吧, 怪胎
Run away, freak!
这是走, 不是逃
This is a walk, not a run.
有人见过他家房子吗?
Anyone ever see his house?
整个地方都是这些垃圾
The whole place is covered with this junk.
魔法符咒和香
Magic charms and incense.
全是他那个疯子奶奶的
It's his crazy grandma's.
她是什么人, 某种巫婆吗?
What is she, some kind of witch?
好吧, 我说真的, 能不能别把我奶奶扯进来?
Okay, for real, can we leave my grandma out of this?
不然怎样
Or what?
说 "我奶奶是个疯巫婆"
Say, "My grandma's a crazy witch."
你奶奶是个疯巫婆?
Your grandma's a crazy witch?
等等 不 不 不
Wait. No, no, no! Your...
给你们好看的 你和你的巫婆奶奶
This is what you get. You and your witchy grandma.
我告诉过你, 别把我奶奶扯进来!
I told you, leave my grandma out of it!
你看到了吗?
You see that?
你可以看到他的内裤
You can see his underwear.
怎么回事?
What is happening?
哟! 搏击大师
Yo! Fight Club!
没事的 只有我一个
It's okay. It's just me.
是啊 你吓我一跳
Yeah. Well, you snuck up on me.
我是拉芙
I'm Rav.
我是汤姆
I'm Tom.
是的, 你刚才说过了
Yeah, you mentioned that earlier,
就在你把一个家伙扔上天花板之前 忘了?
right before you threw a dude into the ceiling. Hello?
你知道, 也许是我今天早上吃蛋白棒吃的
You know, maybe it's that protein bar I had this morning.
哇哦 我得买一根那种的
Wow. I gotta get one of those.
-  等我?  - 好吧
-  Wait for me?  -  Okay.
你好
Hi.
我跟她说了我走回去
I told her I'd walk home.
我们走 走吧
Let's go. Come on.
来了
Got you.
Put the studio In the mansion
Pull up In a new high fashion
Pull up just like "Ooh, you a baddie"
Imagine
这是你奶奶做的?
So your grandma makes these?
哇
Wow.
我的养母, 她也很喜欢这些东西
My foster mom, she loves these things.
实际上, 我奶奶有一套关于它们如何能辟邪的整套故事
My grandma's actually got a whole story about how they ward off evil spirits.
好了 就此打住 邪灵?
Okay, stop right there. Evil spirits?
对不起! 借过
Sorry! Coming through!
你知道奶奶们总是讲些最疯狂的故事
You know how grandmas always tell the craziest stories.
是的, 事实上, 我不知道
Yeah, actually, I don't.
-  哦, 对不起 我不是故意...  - 没事的
-  Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...   -  It's all good.
我终于中了寄养大奖
I finally hit the foster jackpot.
我现在住的地方非常棒
The place I'm at now is pretty rad.
太酷了
That's cool.
我奶奶在我很小的时候就收留了我
My grandma took me in when I was super little.
但她很棒
But she's great.
-  你知道, 她可以...  - 什么? 古怪又尴尬?
-  You know, she can be...   -  What? Weird and embarrassing?
是啊 但她也很酷
Yeah. But she's cool too.
我情愿和一个酷女巫住在一起
I'd go live with a cool witch any day.
我牙齿里有东西吗?
Do I have something in my teeth?
没有 啥也没有
Nope. You're good.
那现在呢?
How 'bout now?
嘿, 吉吉
Hey, Gigi.
哦, 那家伙还好吗? 她应该是那个样子的吗?
Ooh, is that thing okay? Should she look like that?
是啊 是啊 她喜欢睁着眼睛睡觉
Yeah, yeah. She just, you know, sleeps with her eyes open.
再见, 吉吉
Bye, Gigi!
你的眼睛一定很干, 狗狗
Your eyes must be so dry, dog.
请你现在就回头吧
Please just turn back now.
一旦看到, 你就忘不掉了
Once you see it, you can't unsee it.
别这样 汤姆 我肯定没事的
Oh, come on, Tom. I'm sure it's fine.
就因为我那特别正常的房子 有人要打我
People beat me up because of my totally normal house.
不会那么糟糕的
It can't be that bad.
哦, 该死
Oh, dang.
很多人把橘子放在我们的门廊上
A lot of people leave oranges on our stoop
因为他们认为我们的房子是一座寺庙
because they think our house is a temple.
不过好的一面是, 橘子免费
But on the plus side, free oranges.
嘿, 汤米
Hey, Tommy!
嘿, 你朋友是谁? 她看起来好可爱
Hey! Who's your friend? She looks so cute.
哦 嗨 汤姆的奶奶
Oh. Hi, Tom's grandma.
杀了我吧
Kill me now.
汤姆, 你应该请她进来
Ah Tom, you should invite her in.
好的, 我马上来, 阿嫲
All right. I'll be right there, Ah Ma!
明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
你父母就是在高中认识的哦
You know, your parents met in high school.
阿嫲, 别激动
Ah Ma, chill.
她只是个朋友, 好吗?
She's just a friend, okay?
反正她可能也被我们的怪屋子吓跑了
She probably got scared off anyway by our crazy house.
哪里怪了?
Crazy amazing?
还好她没看到里面
At least she didn't see the inside.
汤姆, 虽然这些符咒在你看来很傻
Tom, even if these charms seem silly to you,
但这些对我很重要
they are important to me.
我还是搞不懂它们什么意思
I still don't even know what they mean.
你不需要懂就能理解
You don't have to know to understand.
阿嫲, 你在跟我打哑谜
Ah Ma, you're talking to me in riddles.
有一天
One day,
总有一天, 你会看到真实的自己
you will see yourself for what you truly are
而不仅仅只是表面上的
and not what you appear to be.
这又是什么意思?
And what does that mean?
我们讨论过这个问题
We talked about this.
汤姆, 我们不用这个
Ah Tom, we don't use these.
我们用这个和这个
We use this and this.
我们不必战斗
We don't have to fight.
再说, 你也不擅长这个
Besides, you're not too good at it.
那孩子说你是巫婆
The kid called you a witch.
所以呢? 也许我是个巫婆
So? Maybe I am a witch.
哈哈 非常有趣
Ha-ha. Very funny.
学校里的这个恶霸, 他需要你的同情
This bully at school, he needs your compassion.
什么? 为什么?
What? Why?
因为他自己可能也曾受过伤
Because he himself was probably hurt at some point.
人之初, 性本善, 汤姆
People are inherently good, Tom.
我们家族一直坚信这一点
Our family has always believed this.
哪有什么家庭? 只有你和我
What family? It's just you and me.
你的血统可以追溯到千秋万代
Your lineage goes back a thousand generations.
我们的传统在你的身上生生不息
Our traditions live on in you.
是啊, 也许我们可以试着不那么传统一次
Yeah, well, maybe we could try being a little less traditional for once.
显然 我为此感到自豪 或者管他呢
Obviously, I'm proud of it or whatever.
"或者管他呢"?
"Or whatever"?
我只想做个普通人
I just wanna be normal.
汤姆, 你可不普通
Ah Tom, you are not normal.
太好了 谢谢
Great. Thanks.
我们全家都很不普通
Our entire family is very not normal.
我等着和你谈这件事已经很久了
I've been waiting to talk to you about this for a long time.
但首先, 你必须把这些符咒重新挂起来
But first, you must put the charms back up.
然后, 我们再谈
And then, we'll talk.
好的 奶奶
Okay, Grandma.
快点
Hurry up!
你不能就这样把它们放在一起
You can't just put them up like that.
哇, 老兄
Whoa, dude!
有讲究的
There's a system.
你是谁?
Who are you?
护身符拿下多久了?
How long were the protective charms down?
就五分钟, 好吗?
Like, for five minutes, okay?
-  我认识你吗?  - 不认识
-  Do I know you, man?   -  No.
但我认识你
But I know you.
哇哦! 你在闻我吗?
Whoa! Ew! Are you sniffing me?
- 是啊  - 你臭死了, 孩子
- Yeah.   - And you reek, kid.
不, 我不臭
No, I don't.
你奶奶呢? 李太太, 你还好吗?
Where's your grandmother? Mrs. Lee, are you okay?
伙计 好吧
Dude. Okay.
别脱鞋 一点也不粗鲁
Keep your shoes on. That's not rude at all.
好了 你踩了一地脚印 好吗
There we go. So you have tracking mud and all that stuff, okay.
- 虎!  - 美玲
- Hu!   - Mei Ling.
见到你真高兴
It's so good to see you.
别掐了, 好吗? 我们说过这事
No pinching necessary, all right? We spoke about this.
汤姆, 这是我的老朋友虎
Tom, this is Hu, my old friend.
老朋友?
An old friend?
比如, 我们在这说的是哪种朋友?
Like, what kind of friend are we talking here?
希望是柏拉图式的
Platonic, hopefully.
唉, 没时间废话了
Ugh, there's no time for this.
今天, 我在孩子的学校闻到了法术的味道
I picked up the scent of fashu at the boy's school today.
魔法?
Magic?
我知道 我也感觉到了
I know. I felt it too.
他一身味道 你可能有危险的
He stinks of it. You could be in danger.
冷静点
Calm down.
我们正要好好谈谈"那个"
We were just about to have "the talk."
阿嫲 不 我不需要谈那个 我才𝟏𝟓岁
Ew. Ah Ma, no, I don't need the talk. I'm 𝟏𝟓.
所以符咒被卸了, 孩子却还不知道自己是谁
So the charms are down, the kid still doesn't know who he is,
十二生肖没有一个人遵守我的任何守则
and none of the Zodiacs have been following any of my protocols.
汤姆 你今天打过架 到底是怎么回事?
Tom, your fight today. What exactly happened?
有个孩子, 他对我发火了
I mean, this kid, he got all mad at me.
大块头 你知道吗 肩膀都鼓起来了 有点像你
Huge guy, you know? Shoulders all puffed out. Kinda like you actually.
切入正题
Cut to the chase.
不是我的错 是这孩子先动手的
It wasn't me. This kid, he started it.
- 你打赢了吗?  - 什么?
- Did you finish it?  - What?
有什么奇怪的事情发生吗?
Did anything strange happen?
嗯...没有, 真没有
Yeah... No, not really.
除了我把他扔上天花板的时候
Other than when I threw him into the ceiling.
哦, 天哪
Oh, boy.
等一下 没被别人看到 对吧?
Wait. Nobody saw you, right?
没有 真没有 只有大概一百多个孩子吧
No, no, not really. Just about a hundred kids or so.
我们得离开这里
Oh, we gotta get out of here.
奶奶, 这家伙是谁?
Grandma, who is this guy?
"这家伙"?
"This guy"?
我是誓死保护凤凰守护者的
I'm a Warrior of the Circle of Twelve,
十二生肖中的一员
sworn to protect the Guardian of the Phoenix.
阿嫲, 就像童话故事里的?
Ah Ma, like from the kids' stories?
我是一个生肖
I'm a Zodiac.
好的 你好 我是汤姆 李家的
Okay. Hi. I'm Tom, House of Lee.
乳糖不耐症患者, 斯蒂芬·库里新秀卡的守护者
Lactose-intolerant and guardian of a Steph Curry rookie card.
"童话故事"?
"Kids' stories"?
我想给他一点时间
I wanted to give him time.
什么时间?
Time for what?
真的吗? 伙计们 嘿 我就在这儿
Seriously? Guys! Hello! I'm right here.
我们知道 孩子 我们知道你在这里
We know, kid. We know you're here.
老兄, 你有什么问题吧?
Dude, what is your problem?
每个人都知道你在这里
Everybody knows you're here!
你这话有什么意思吗?
Does anything you say make sense?
我说的每句话都有意思
Everything I say makes sense.
有人来了
Something's here.
- 哇 哇 地震  - 不是
- Whoa! Whoa, whoa, earthquake!   - Nope.
穿上你的鞋, 汤姆
Put on your shoes, Tom.
你是怎么做到的?
How did you do that?
哇哦
Whoa.
- 阿嫲  - 哦, 对
- Ah Ma.  - Oh, yeah!
我负责前面, 你负责后面
I'll cover the front, you get the back.
不, 这法术太强大了
No. This is powerful fashu.
你和汤姆得走了
You and Tom need to go.
什么? 不
What? No!
把他带到安全的地方 他需要你 虎
Get him to safety. He needs you, Hu.
汤姆 汤姆 看着我
Tom. Tom, look at me.
我保证会解释一切的
I promise I'll explain everything,
但现在你必须跟虎一起走
but right now you have to go with Hu.
我不会离开你的
I'm not leaving you.
- 鹿  - 快走 现在就走
- Loo.   - Go! Now!
- 不, 等等...  - 走吧
- No, wait...  - Go!
哇哦
Whoa!
李太太
Mrs. Lee.
鹿
Loo.
我们可以别搞得太复杂
We can make this easy.
你知道我想要什么, 老太太
You know what I want, old woman.
那就来拿吧
Then come and get it.
上
Go!
把凤凰石给我拿来
Bring me the Phoenix.
真宝贵啊
How precious.
奶奶
Grandma!
哇哦 哇哦
Whoa. Whoa.
哦 哇哦 不 不 不
Oh, whoa! No, no, no, no, no!
退后
Back off!
哦, 好怀念这一切
Oh, I really missed doing that.
你的裤子哪去了?
What happened to your pants?
哦, 太好了 更多妖怪
Oh, great. More yaoguai.
什么是妖....?
What the heck is a yao...
现在没有生肖勇士保护你了
No Zodiac Warriors to protect you now.
只有你和我
Just you and me.
除非你想让我拿你亲爱的孙子下手
Unless you prefer I start with your darling grandson.
离他远点
Stay away from him!
加油 驾 老虎
Come on! Come on! Giddyap, tiger!
你再说一遍, 我就吃了你
Say that again, and I will eat you.
不 不 等等 等等 等一下
No, no, no, no. Wait, wait, wait! Hold on!
不 不 我的天啊
No, no, no! Oh, my gosh!
不 不 放开我...
No, no, no! Get off my...
噢 往哪踢呢
Ow! Watch what you're kicking.
老虎 老虎 救命
Tiger! Tiger, help!
看看你, 现在这么脆弱
Look at you, so fragile now.
这么老了
So old.
需要帮一把吗?
Do you need a hand?
我给你两把!
I'll give you two!
- 刚好掉在用过的尿布上  - 阿嫲
- Right on a used diaper.  - Ah Ma!
阿嫲
Ah Ma!
阿汤, 你还好吗?
Ah Tom, are you okay?
你以为我那么容易被打败吗?
You think I'm so easily defeated?
我要拿走这个
I'll take that.
不 放开她
No! Let her go!
只要我是守护者 你就休想
Not while I'm Guardian!
阿嫲
Ah Ma.
什么?
What?
那是什么?
What is that?
灵魂引渡车
The Ghost Cart.
来接走伟大崇高者的灵魂
Comes to carry away the souls of the great and the noble.
阿嫲
Ah Ma!
加油 孩子 跟上
Come on, kid. Keep up.
快进去
Quick, inside.
我必须警告其他人
I have to alert the others.
这有什么用? 不, 不, 我们需要...
What good is that gonna do? No. No, we need to...
- 我们怎么会在废品店?  - 古董店
- Why are we in a junk shop?  - Antique shop.
不是垃圾
Not junk.
我住在这里
I live here.
我一直在这里守护着你
I've been here watching over you.
你和那些怪物...
You and those monsters...
妖怪鹿的手下 凶恶的小玩意
Yaoguai. Loo's creatures. Vicious little creatures.
这都是小时候我奶奶给我讲过的疯狂的故事
They were just crazy stories my grandma told me when I was little.
他们不是故事, 好吗?
Well, they're not stories, okay?
不是故事, 孩子
Not stories, kid.
你奶奶是一位守护者, 汤姆
Your grandmother was a Guardian, Tom.
最厉害的之一
One of the best.
她用生命保护了那个
She gave her life to protect that.
她的项链?
Her necklace?
是凤凰石
It's the Phoenix.
自从女神女娲用凤凰石创造了人类
Ever since goddess Nu Kua used the Phoenix to create humanity,
黑暗势力一直试图抢走它
dark forces have been trying to capture it.
现在, 保护它的责任就交给你了
Now the duty of protecting it is yours.
什么? 这不是...
What? That's not...
我得回家了 我明天还要上学
I have to go home. I have school tomorrow.
而奶奶, 她...
And Grandma, she's...
你不能走 孩子
You can't leave, kid.
这是我的工作
It's my job.
我都不认识你, 老兄
I don't even know you, man.
如果你是生肖战士, 我以为你的职责是保护阿嫲!
If you're a Zodiac Warrior, I thought your job was to protect Ah Ma!
- 汤姆...  - 你把她扔在了那里 你本可以救她的
- Tom... - You left her there! You could've saved her.
嘿
Hey.
- 我得离开这里  - 别走 别 别
- I gotta get out of here.  - Stop. No, no.
- 你不能走...等等  - 放开我
- You can't go... Wait.  - Get off of me!
不  不 你需要知道...
No, no, no. You need to know about...
门上的出门咒
the exit spell on the door.
李太太让我照顾你
Mrs. Lee put you in my care.
这样你就是我的徒弟了
That makes you my apprentice.
楼上有个房间 你就住那
There's a room upstairs. Why don't you take it?
很好
Fine.
笨蛋老虎
Dumb tiger.
这不可能是真的
This can't be happening.
只是一条垃圾项链
Just a junky necklace.
哇哦
Whoa!
拜托
Come on!
尔等何人胆敢唤醒本皇女娲?
Who dares wake the Empress Nu Kua?
汤姆?
Um, Tom?
是你啊
Oh, it's you.
你现在行走在两个世界之间...
You walk two worlds now...
凡人世界和魔法世界
the mortal world and the world of magic.
好的
Okay.
我真的被搞糊涂了
I really am losing it.
我以为她会没事的
I thought she was gonna be okay.
对不起, 孩子
I'm sorry, kid.
我不知道现在的香里都加了些什么
I don't know what they put in incense these days,
真的很刺激我的眼睛
but it really irritates my eyes.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊, 我也是
Yeah, me too.
嘿 汤姆?
Psst. Hey. Tom?
汤姆 孩子
Tom. Kid!
醒醒吧
Wake up already!
嗷 剪剪指甲
Ow. Cut your nails.
搞什么鬼? 你就是这样叫醒别人的吗?
What the heck? Is that how you wake people up?
好吧, 下次我给你唱首歌
Well, next time I'll sing you a song.
来吧 该做事了
Now, come on. Time to get to work.
做事? 我不知道你是怎么想学徒的这些事的
Work? I don't know what you're thinking with all this apprentice stuff,
但我是不会帮你给车打蜡的, 伙计
but I'm not waxing cars for you, man.
我知道这很酷 来吧
I know it's cool. Come on.
让我看看你有什么本事
I need to see what I'm working with.
- 打我试试  - 什么? 来真的?
- Try to hit me.   - What? For real?
除非你觉得自己不是这块料
Unless you don't think you're up for it.
哦, 开始了, 毛毛脸!
Oh, it's on, fur face!
你必须做得更好
You'll have to do better than that.
你以为妖怪就会站在那里等你打吗?
You think a yaoguai is just gonna stand there and wait for you?
所以, 我打不到你
So, I can't hit you.
这就是你想说的重点吗?
Is that the big point you're trying to make?
不 关键是 你没抓住重点
No. The point is, you're missing the point.
你刚才到底几次想打我来着?
Exactly how many times did you try to strike me just now?
我不知道
I don't know.
𝟖次.
Eight.
你检查了多少次
And how many times did you check
以确保凤凰石还在你身边?
to make sure that the Phoenix was still with you?
一次也没有
Not once.
这就是我想说的重点
That's the point I'm trying to make.
老鼠
Rat!
我告诉过你别碰我的钱包!
I told you to stay out of my wallet!
滚过来
Get over here!
不, 不, 那东西是前...
No, no, no, no, that thing's ex...
你会为此付出代价的
You're gonna pay for that!
这就是你的下场!
That's what you get!
有多少年...
How many years of...
别再偷我的东西了
Stop stealing my stuff!
你好
Hi there!
天哪, 你看到了吗? 我做到了
Oh, my gosh! Did you see that? I did it!
那招 我使了那招 嘣 嘣 嘣!
The thing! I did the thing, the bow, bow, bow!
别得意 那不过是用来防守的法术
Don't get cocky. That was a defensive fashu.
条件反射
It's reflex.
汤姆, 这是老鼠
Tom, this is Rat.
等等, 他是一个生肖
Wait. He's a Zodiac.
和你一样
He's like you.
你是想侮辱我吗?
Are you trying to insult me?
西德尼是我的名字 收集是我的专长
Sidney's my name. Acquisitions is my game.
收集?
Acquisitions?
- 你是个贼  - 贼?
- You're a thief.  - Thief?
你偷了我的明朝宝剑
You stole my Ming dynasty sword.
- 确保他没把你的表偷走  - 我没有手表
- Make sure he didn't steal your watch.   - I don't have a watch.
没问题 我有一堆 想要吗? 我给你友情价
No problem. I got a bunch. Want one? I'll give you friend prices.
西德尼, 你来这里做什么?
Sidney, what are you doing here?
又变回老鼠了 好吧
And we're going with rat again. Okay.
虎 我就是来告诉你 我昨晚看到鹿了
Hu, that's what I came to tell you. I saw Loo last night.
什么?
What?
西德, 这是不可能的
Sid, that's not possible.
我们亲眼看见她死了
We saw her die.
那会我在海边悬崖
I was out wandering around the old high-rent district
老旧的高档社区闲逛
by the sea cliffs.
他们那有最精致的垃圾
They got the most exquisite trash.
我在水沟里找到了最美味的蛤蜊汤
I found a primo clam chowder in the gutter.
然后 不知从哪儿冒出来了 鹿!
And then, out of nowhere, there's Loo!
就在一座废弃的宅邸那, 我想
It was at this abandoned mansion, and I thought,
"她也是来吃蛤蜊汤的吗?
"Now, is she here for the clam chowder too?"
她看起来很恶心
She looked disgusting.
我不是随便乱说的
And I don't just throw that word around.
她爬进了一个令人毛骨悚然的喷泉
She crawled into this creepy fountain,
然后那水, 虎, 治好了她
and the water, Hu, it healed her!
然后, 我直奔这里来了
Obviously, I came straight here.
我知道那个地方 我们还等什么? 我们去抓住她
I know that place. What are we waiting for? Let's go get her.
- 什么? 不  - 为什么不?
- What? No!   - Why not?
因为你会送命的
Because you're gonna get yourself killed.
鹿不只是另一个 "妖怪"
Loo isn't just another yaoguai.
她就像守护者一样强大
She's as powerful as a Guardian.
她掌握着最黑暗的魔法
She can access the darkest magic.
我们应该去神殿 叫上剩下的生肖
We should go to the temple and get the rest of the Zodiacs.
没错 就这么办 生肖队大集合
Exactly! Let's do that. Team Zodiac assemble!
我一个人干更好
I work better alone.
来吧 虎 你知道和我们大家在一起
Come on, Hu. You know it'll be safer for him
他会更安全
with all of us together.
好吧 我们去找生肖们
Fine. We'll go get the Zodiacs.
好!
Yes!
我已经后悔了
I already regret this.
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
给你准备了一份给新任守护者的小礼物
Got a little new Guardian gift for ya.
哎呀 不是这个
Whoops! That's not it!
在公交车上发现的, 好东西
Found that on the bus, so you know it's good.
你可能需要这个
You might need this.
记住, 不是我给你的
Now, remember, you didn't get this from me.
哇哦
Whoa.
是明朝的吗?
Is that Ming dynasty?
漂亮
Sweet!
唐人街是世界上最美味的地方!
Chinatown is the most delicious place in the world!
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你闻到了吗?
Do you smell that?
腐烂的鱼, 飞溅的酱油
Rotting fish, splattered soy sauce.
粗鲁!
Rude!
那是发霉的人参吗?
Is that moldy ginseng?
饺子 你能相信有人把这些扔掉吗?
Dumplings! Can you believe someone threw these out?
来吧 老鼠
Come on, Rat.
是的!
Yes!
来了 等等 我们要吃点心?
There it is. Wait, we're getting dim sum?
没有那么简单的事情, 孩子
Not everything is what it seems, kid.
就一个
It's only one of them.
别怕 我能对付...
I'm pretty sure I can handle...
- 糟了  - 没有那么简单的事情, 对吧?
- Crap.  - Not everything is what it seems, right?
哦, 是的
Oh, yeah.
惹到老虎, 必遭虎抓
Mess with the Tiger, you get the claws.
- 什么? 没这说法  - 有的
- What? That's not a thing.   - Yes, it is.
- 不 没有 没人这么说  - 老虎就这么说
- No, it isn't. No one says that.  - Tigers do.
哇哦
Whoa.
是你
Oh, you!
什么?
What?
啊 来吧 放马过来
Ah. Come on. Let's do this!
炫耀
Show-off.
好 好 你会飞
Yeah, yeah, you can fly.
哟 太不可思议了
Yo! That was incredible!
先生们
Gentlemen.
米斯特拉尔
Mistral.
你不来, 我也搞得定
I was doing just fine without you.
是的, 我看到了
Yes, I saw.
很高兴见到你, 啮齿动物
It's good to see you, rodent.
她叫我 "啮齿动物"
She called me "rodent."
托马斯·李
Thomas Lee.
我很荣幸能保护你, 指导你
It will be my honor to protect you and guide you.
嘿! 李太太把他托付给我
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey! Mrs. Lee entrusted him to me.
所以, 我才是那个看护和指导他的人
So I'll be the one watching over and guiding him.
哦 就像你指引他走进这个陷阱一样?
Oh. Like you guided him into this trap?
好吧, 听着, 我要带孩子去神殿
Okay, look, I'm taking the kid to the temple.
好主意
Good idea.
你也许可以在那里给他找个没那么多疑的师傅
You can probably find him a master there with fewer trust issues.
你知道吗? 没人邀请你
You know what? Nobody asked you.
邀请我干嘛? 来搭救你?
Asked me what? To save you?
顺便说一句, 不客气
You're welcome, by the way.
小龙就是控制不住自己, 不是吗?
Dragon just can't help herself, can she?
哦, 还是那个老虎
Oh, same old Hu.
关于老虎和它的条纹有什么说法来着?
What's the saying about the tiger and his stripes?
你太歇斯底里了
You're hysterical.
我知道
I know.
辛西娅
Cynthia!
- 我们关门了  - 什么?
- We are closed.  - What?
跟我说说你是怎么处理这些事的吧
Tell me more about how you have all this handled.
辛西娅 是我 老虎
Cynthia, it's me, Tiger.
是虎
It's Hu.
开门啊
Open the door.
你让我很尴尬
You're embarrassing me out here.
停业了
Closed!
这是有关生肖的事情
This is Zodiac business.
这里是有关点心的事情
And this is dim sum business.
我们三小时后开张
And we open in three hours.
干得漂亮
Nicely done.
有谁喜欢你吗?
Does anybody like you?
我知道如何处理这个问题
I know how to deal with this.
作为交换条件, 我会给你一棵 𝟔𝟓 年的野山参
In exchange for entry, I offer you this 𝟔𝟓-year-old wild ginseng.
嘿, 老鼠, 别再偷酱油了
Hey, Rat, no more stealing soy sauce.
你确定不是把我和另一只会说话的老鼠搞混了?
Are you sure you're not confusing me with another talking rat?
一百块可以吗?
Will a hundred bucks do?
我们刚开张 请进
We just opened! Come in.
- 啥也别说了  - 不客气
- Not a word.  - You're welcome.
闻起来真香 我们能停下来吃个叉烧包吗?
Oh, that smells so good. Could we, like, stop and get a char siu bao?
- 不行  - 原谅虎吧
- Nope.  - Forgive Hu.
他理解不了人类
He doesn't understand humans.
或者感情 或者现代世界
Or feelings. Or the modern world.
还有其他很多东西 实话告诉你
Or much of anything, to tell you the truth.
这小子身上一股狐臭和新法术的味道 他是谁?
Boy reeks like armpits and new magic. Who is he?
- 他需要我的保护  - 我们的保护
- He's under my protection.  - Our protection.
生肖们
Zodiacs.
嗯, 这是怎么回事?
Hmm, so what's going on here?
十二神殿在冰柜里? 真的吗?
The Temple of the Twelve is inside a freezer? Really?
天灵灵 地灵灵 左灵灵 右灵灵
开门
时候到了
It's been a minute.
嘿, 谢谢你的包子
Hey, thanks for the bun.
你要多吃点  太瘦了
You needed it. Too skinny!
哦 她是只青蛙
Oh. She's a frog.
哇哦
Whoa.
欢迎来到十二神殿
Welcome to the Temple of the Twelve.
哦 这就是你们的魔法堡垒?
Ooh. So this is like your magical fortress?
这才哪跟哪啊
You ain't seen nothing yet.
现在介绍我们的首发阵容
And now, introducing our starting lineup.
我们是什么, 篮球队吗?
What are we, a basketball team?
让耗子显摆去吧
Let Rat do his thing.
带来令人赞叹的
Presenting the amazing,
令人惊讶的生肖勇士!
the astonishing Zodiac Warriors!
首先, 这位是为您吹响起床号的"早起的鸟儿"先生...
First up, here is your wake-up call from Mr. Early Bird himself...
公鸡
Rooster!
狂怒羽翼
Feathers of fury!
哇哦
Whoa.
用爪子挠进你的心
Pawing his way into your heart,
你们肯定爱他, 臭哄哄的
you gotta love him, stinky breath and all,
狗
Dog!
口水海啸
Slobber tsunami!
下一个是大块头, 浑身肌肉, 勇猛好斗
Next is the big guy, all muscle and tussle,
势不可挡的公牛
the unstoppable Ox!
竖起你的大拇指, 为这位人猿魔女喝彩∶猴子
Put your opposable thumbs up for the simian sorceress herself: Monkey!
变大为小的压缩神机
The lean, mean shrinking machine!
她一身排骨样, 胃大吃四方! 猪
She puts the pork in chop and the belly in flop! Pig!
火腿大连环
The ham slam!
暖场的来了 她是火焰的狂热爱好者
Bringing the heat, she's the maniac of pyro.
- 掌声有请...  - 太热了 候不住了
- Give it up for...  - Too hot to handle.
龙
Dragon!
- 很不错啊 真的  - 别起哄了
- That's not bad, actually.  - Don't encourage this.
只要你张嘴, 她就会听到
If you said it, she's heard it.
可爱的兔子
The adorable Rabbit!
可爱攻击
Cute attack!
万般灵活, 毒舌獠牙
She's flexible, she's fanged,
你绝对不想在睡袋里发现她!
and you definitely don't want to find her in your sleeping bag!
蛇
Snake!
让我们纠缠起来
Let's snuggle.
纯种极速∶马!
The thoroughbred of speed: Horse!
最大马力
Maximum horsepower!
我们的爆破专家
Our explosives expert,
爆炸 "咩咩 "
the "baaa" of boom...
山羊
Goat!
还有, 他是认真的
And he's serious,
复杂的, 自私的....
he's complicated, he's selfish...
就到这吧 表演结束了 老鼠
That's it. Show's over, Rat.
我要把他们叫进来了
I'm bringing them in.
粗鲁
Rude.
咦? 真奇怪 通常我们都是𝟏𝟐个人一起的
Huh. That's weird. Usually there's all 𝟏𝟐 of us.
就这?
This is it?
这连宠物动物园都算不上
This is barely a petting zoo.
- 这孩子是谁?  - 这是汤姆
- Who's the kid?  - This is Tom.
- 他现在是守护者了  - 嘿
- He's the Guardian now.  - Hey.
新守护者, 嗯?
New Guardian, huh?
你要笑死我吗?
Are you pulling my feathers?
看看这孩子 他毛还没长齐呢
Look at this kid. He's barely hatched.
一只小鸡还说我
Says a chicken.
我是一只公鸡 听到了吗?
I'm a rooster! You hear me?
- 大公鸡  - 你能别叽歪了吗?
- A rooster!  -  Will you knock it off?
上次我们咯咯叫时, 你说
Last time we clucked, you said
你一个人就能保护守护者
you could protect the Guardian all by yourself.
对吧, 山羊?
Isn't that right, Goat?
在室内别玩爆破
No explosions indoors.
你们要帮我吗? 鹿必须为她的所作所为付出代价
Are you guys gonna help me? Loo has to pay for what she's done.
孩子 这不是复仇 守护者不是干这个的
Kid, this isn't about revenge. That's not what Guardians do.
也许他们应该干这个
Well, maybe they should.
你就呆在神殿里吧
You're staying here in the temple.
- 我们来对付鹿  - 什么? 不!
- We'll deal with Loo.  - What? No!
哇 哇 我是不是错过了一个
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Did I miss a meeting
有人决定让虎须先生当领袖的会议?
where someone put Mr. Whiskers in charge?
相信我, 棒槌, 我也不想和你待在一起
Believe me, drumsticks, I don't wanna be here with you either.
棒槌?
Drumsticks?
让你尝尝棒槌的味道
I'll show you what drumsticks taste like!
要我把你们两个缩小点吗?
Do I need to knock you two down a size?
伙计们 嘿 嘿
Guys. Hey. Hey!
好吧, 如果你想让我给你看...
Fine! If you want me to show you...
真可爱
That's adorable.
帮倒忙, 娜奥米
Not helping, Naomi.
你以为自己高大威猛?
Think you're so big and tough?
公鸡经常把猫干掉
Roosters take out cats all the time.
活了几千岁了, 你们还像个孩子
Thousands of years old, and you still behave like children.
这么小 这么愤怒
So tiny. And so angry.
你离死亡只有一步之遥 死亡之啄
You're one peck away from death. The death peck.
好吧, 你很幸运, 你不是我的午餐
Well, you're lucky you're not lunch.
汤姆哪去了?
Hey! Where's Tom?
他去哪儿了? 兔子?
Where'd he go? Rabbit?
好吧, 我听到跑步声了
Okay. I hear running.
走进小巷, ...
Into the alley and...
那孩子真把我们甩了
The kid totally ghosted us.
是的, 他走了
Yeah, he's gone.
来吧 我们不能失去他
Come on. We can't lose him.
对不起
Sorry.
等等, 你不会也会说话吧?
Wait, you don't talk too, do you?
你当然不会
Of course you don't.
松鼠不会说话, 只有老虎 老鼠 猴子和龙才会
Squirrels don't talk, just tigers and rats and monkeys and dragons.
哇哦
Whoa!
什么...
What the...
汤姆
Tom!
如果我知道这个地方
If I had known this place
里面如此漂亮, 我早就把它抢走了
was so nice on the inside, I would have robbed it a long time ago.
这一切都是幻觉
It's all an illusion.
这里有黑暗法术在起作用
There's dark fashu at work here.
我们分头行动 这样我们更容易找到他
Let's split up. We can cover more ground that way.
不, 我们在一起更强大
No. We're stronger together.
好吧 我们一起
Fine. We'll stick together.
但一人一边
But separately.
那还叫什么一起?
How is that sticking together?
只有我一个人听到这些吗?
Am I the only one who's hearing this?
每个人都能听到, 毛球
Everybody can hear it, furball!
那你很棒哦, 但还是我这耳朵听起来更舒服
I'm so happy for you, but it sounds better in my ears.
Look at us, yeah What's your score?
Can't help but look '
Cause we're gonna blow
Jumping the mic Like
it's up in the show
We say hello Hello, hello, hello
天 这走廊可真长
Man, this is a long hallway!
You lose your mind
We say hello Hello, hello, hello
Hola, hola, konnichiwa
山羊
Goat!
其他生肖
The other Zodiacs!
一定是鹿抓住了它们
Loo must have captured them.
听好了 我的耳朵能搞定
Listen up! My ears got this!
快走 去找其他人
Go! Find the others!
没问题
I'm on it.
好吧, 雨伞!
Okay, umbrella!
准备被扇吧
Get ready for some wings!
拉芙?
Rav?
汤姆 嘿 嗯...
Tom! Hi. Um...
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我住在这里
I'm living in here.
你拿的是剑吗? 这是干什么, 角色扮演吗?
Is that a sword you're carrying? What is this, cosplay?
你从没提过你住在闹鬼的宅子里
You never mentioned you lived in a haunted mansion.
- 闹鬼?  - 拉芙
- Haunted?  - Rav.
你不把我介绍给你的小朋友吗?
Aren't you going to introduce me to your little friend?
嗯 对不起 这是汤姆
Yeah, sorry. This is Tom.
汤姆, 这是我的养母, 鹿
Tom, this is my foster mother, Loo.
鹿?
Loo?
汤姆 你在干什么?
Tom! What are you doing?
你好 托马斯
Hello, Thomas.
你真的很讨人喜欢
You are truly a delight.
搞什么鬼?
What the heck?
你是什么东西?
What are you?
走
Go!
他戴着项链, 拉芙
He's wearing a necklace, Rav.
我停不下来!
I can't stop!
现在就拿给我
Bring it to me now.
汤姆, 我...
Tom, I...
项链, 拉芙?
The necklace, Rav?
- 他没戴  - 什么?
- He's not wearing one.  - What?
什么都没有 让他走吧
He doesn't have anything! Just let him go!
够了
Enough!
- 拉芙  - 凤凰石在哪里?
- Rav!  - Where is the Phoenix?
汤姆
Tom!
我已经寻找凤凰石上千年了 托马斯
I've been searching for the Phoenix for a thousand years, Thomas.
告诉我在哪儿, 我就饶了你
Tell me where it is, and I'll spare you.
你 还有可爱又愚蠢的拉芙
You and sweet, stupid Rav.
告诉我在哪里
Tell me where it is!
好的 拜托 等等
Okay, okay. Please, wait.
等等
Wait.
它就在我家门廊的石头下面
It's under a rock on my porch.
等等 不 其实它在我口袋里
Wait, wait. No, no, it's actually inside my pocket.
也有可能在我的袜子里...
Unless it's inside my sock...
你以为我是傻瓜吗?
You think I'm a fool?
不, 肯定在我帽子里
No. For sure it's in my hat.
等等, 我没戴帽子
Wait, I'm not wearing a hat.
汤姆
Tom!
老虎
Tiger.
龙
Dragon.
老鼠
Rat.
猴子在哪里?
Where's Monkey?
啊, 完美
Ah, perfect.
等你们最后一个生肖和小托马斯一起死在这里
When the last of you Zodiac die here with young Thomas,
就没人能阻止我找到它了
there will be no one left to stop me from finding it.
什么情况?
What's happening?
大家都扶好
Everyone hold on to something!
哇哦
Whoa!
噢 西德尼 那是我的剑吗?
Ow! Sidney! Is that my sword?
什么?
What?
大家都会游泳, 对吧?
Uh, everyone can swim, right?
游泳 会 在水下呼吸 不会
Swim? Yes. Breathe underwater? No!
伙计们, 我想我找到出路了
Guys, I think I found a way out,
但可能只有我能通过
but I might be the only one who can fit.
哦 我能让我们都通过的 大家抓紧了
Oh, I'll make us fit. Everyone, hold tight!
来吧
Come on!
好的
Okay.
嗯, 纳奥米, 这个缩小咒有过期时间吗?
Um, Naomi, does this shrinking spell have an expiration date?
神圣的虾仁炒饭
Holy shrimp fried rice!
我觉得好奇怪
I feel so weird.
我们可能有麻烦了!
We may have a problem!
快点, 龙
Hurry, Dragon!
什么?
What?
干得好, 娜奥米
Well done, Naomi.
伙计们? 伙计们?
Guys? Guys?
有人吗?
Anyone?
汤姆, 我...
Tom, I...
谢谢你救了我
Thank you for saving me.
我看不见了 一片漆黑
I can't see! It's all darkness!
哦, 这就是大结局吗?
Oh, is this the end?
呼! 好了, 一切顺利
Phew! Well, that went great.
妖怪
Yaoguai.
汤姆 这事关重大 你把凤凰石藏哪儿了?
Tom, now this is very important. Where'd you stash the Phoenix?
一个幸运的地方
Someplace lucky.
希望如此
I-I hope.
在一罐幸运饼干里?
In a bowl of fortune cookies?
超级聪明, 对吧?
Super smart, right?
我想这是 "幸运", 没人会吃了它!
I guess it's "fortunate",  nobody ate it!
我觉得这很好笑
I thought it was funny.
这样的餐垫我见得多了
I've seen place mats like these all my life.
原来, 他们都是以你们为原型的
And the whole time, they were based on you guys.
差太远了
Loosely based.
看看这个
Look at this.
这是什么, 香肠? 有腿的?
What is this, a sausage? With legs?
我脸上可没有毛
I do not have facial hair.
我有 我看起来很不错
I do. And I look good.
我想念猪了
I miss Pig.
我想念他们所有人
I miss them all.
他们是我们的家人
They're our family.
我们得救他们
We gotta save them.
无论成为守护者我需要知道什么, 你们都必须教会我
Whatever I need to know to be a Guardian, you have to teach me.
拜托
Please.
通常都是前任守护者来训练继任守护者
The Guardian always trains the next Guardian.
听着, 这孩子说得对
Look, the kid's right.
李太太不在了, 我们也没有太多选择, 不是吗?
Without Mrs. Lee, we don't have much choice, do we?
你的任务就是感应到凤凰
Your job is to connect with the Phoenix.
米斯特拉尔?
Mistral?
哇哦
Whoa.
排除一切杂念
Clear your mind of all distraction.
为了看到凤凰, 你必须集中精力, 汤姆
In order to see the Phoenix, you must focus, Tom.
凤凰的力量是这个宇宙中最强大的
The power of the Phoenix is the greatest in this universe.
在对的人手中, 可以创造万物
In the right hands, it creates.
而在错误的人手中, 比如鹿的手中, 就会摧毁一切
And in the wrong hands, like Loo's, it destroys.
那么 如果她得到了 会怎么样?
So what happens if she gets it?
她会在春节那天释放其力量
She'll unleash its power on Lunar New Year,
那是气最旺的时候
when the chi is at its most potent.
然后利用凤凰毁灭全人类
Then use the Phoenix to destroy all of humanity
并在永恒的黑暗中统治世界
and reign over the world in darkness for all of eternity.
好吧, 听起来确实不妙
Okay, that does sound bad.
如果被释放出来, 碰到它的人必死无疑
If it were ever unleashed, no one could touch it and survive,
甚至连守护者都一样
not even a Guardian.
但戴在脖子上还是可以的 知道了
But it's okay to wear it around my neck, though. Got it.
蒸饺 非常美味
Steamed dumplings. Very delicious.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
- 吃啊  - 我说, 嗯
- Eat it!  - I mean, mmm.
汤姆, 把酱油递给我
Tom, pass me the soy sauce.
不用你的手
Without your hands.
- 怎么做?  - 气
- How?  - Chi lines.
你知道, 这就像是一圈无处不在的神奇能量
You know, it's like strings of magical energy that are everywhere.
你只需抓住一个
You just grab on to one.
像这样
Like this.
哟!
Yo!
你能看到凤凰吗?
Can you see the Phoenix?
不
No.
我很容易受惊
I'm easily scared of everything,
所以护身咒就派上了用场
so protection spells come in handy.
护身咒
Protection spell!
Protection spell.
没有 你能教我用法苏炸东西吗?
Nope. Can you teach me to blast stuff with fashu now?
等等, 等等, 等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
你说什么? 法苏
What did you say? Fashu.
感受你体内的气
Feel the chi inside you.
让它流动起来
And let it flow.
这主意糟透了
Terrible idea.
法书?
Fashu?
法术.
Fashu.
是啊, 法苏.
Yeah, fashu.
法 术
Fashu!
法苏? 你的语调完全不对
Fashu? Your intonation's all wrong.
不
No.
哟 你看到了吗?
Yo! Did you see that?
番...番薯
Fan... Fan-shu.
你刚才说的是 "红薯"!
You just said "sweet potato"!
"红薯"!
"Sweet potato"!
好
Yeah!
甜点
Dessert!
你能看见凤凰吗?
是的!
Yes!
- 真的吗?  - 没有
- Really?  - No.
耶
Yeah!
现在呢?
如果你看不到凤凰, 这一切都毫无意义!
All of this amounts to nothing if you can't see the Phoenix!
- 虎  - 管它呢
- Hu.  - Whatever!
我很抱歉我没能更好地感应到魔法鸟, 好吗?
I'm sorry I can't connect with the magic bird better, okay?
李太太告诉你的所有关于守护者和生肖的故事
All the stories Mrs. Lee told you about the Guardians and the Zodiac
不只是为了哄你入睡
weren't just to get you to sleep.
她在教你, 汤姆
She was teaching you, Tom.
我告诉过你, 我不知道我...
I told you, I didn't know I...
你不需要知道就能理解
You don't need to know to understand.
不如我们都休息一下, 冷静一下
How about we all take a break and cool off.
很好
Fine!
他恨我
He hates me.
你是这么认为的吗?
Is that what you think?
- 虎为你献出了生命  - 什么?
- Hu gave his life for you.  - What?
桥上的那晚 你当时还是个婴儿
That night on the bridge. You were just a baby.
虎以极大的代价救了你的命
Hu saved your life at great cost.
灵魂引渡车为他驶来
The Ghost Cart was coming for him.
只有把自己灵魂的分一部分给他, 与他的灵魂结合在一起
Only by giving him a part of her soul, by joining it with his,
李太太才能救活他
was Mrs. Lee able to save him.
我奶奶的灵魂有一部分在虎身上?
There's a part of my grandma's soul inside Hu?
有时你可以看到 从眼睛里
You can see it sometimes. It's in the eyes.
我印象深刻 他真的进步很大
I'm impressed. He's really coming along.
这还不够, 你知道的
It's not enough, and you know it.
没有守护者教他如何感应到凤凰
Without a Guardian to teach him how to connect with the Phoenix,
其余的都不重要
none of the rest matters.
我们已经尽力了, 虎
We're doing our best, Hu.
但我们不是李太太
But we're not Mrs. Lee.
我观察他很久了
I've been watching him a long time.
你想知道他为什么不能感应到凤凰吗?
You want to know why he can't connect with the Phoenix?
因为他不知道自己是谁
'Cause he doesn't know who he is.
也许他永远不会知道
Maybe he never will.
你好, 一路同行的朋友
Hello, friend from the road
我想写一张纸条
I wanted to write a note
告诉你 总而言之
To let you know that All in all
事情并不是表面上这样
It ain't all what it seems
我觉得人生跌入了低谷
I feel like I've hit a low
一种我从未有过的体验
One I've never hit before
最近, 感觉渺小得像海里的一粒沙
Lately, I been feelin' small As the salt in the sea
哦 要做的事情太多而时间太少
Oh, it's so much to do In so little of time
我觉得我有点落后了
I feel like I fell A little behind
坚持住, 坚持住, 坚持住
Hold up, hold up, hold up
那片海湾似乎遥不可及
It seems so out of reach To place upon the bay
谁曾想我还是去了那里?
Whoever thought I'd get there anyway?
坚持住, 坚持住, 坚持住
Hold up, hold up, hold up
我发现自己难以脱身
I find it hard to get
生活已然如此艰难
Way too hard to live
我回来了, 阿嫲
I'm home, Ah Ma.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你为什么不告诉我?
Why didn't you tell me?
没有你我该怎么办?
How am I supposed to do this without you?
不, 不可能
No. No, that's impossible.
你...你是...
Are... Are you...
真的是你吗?
Is it really you?
你以为他们那么容易就能摆脱我吗?
Did you think they could get rid of me that easily?
阿嫲
Ah Ma.
发生了什么事? 你去哪儿了?
What happened? Where did you go?
留到以后睡前故事时间再讲吧
A bedtime story for later.
现在告诉我, 我的项链还在吗?
Now tell me, do you still have my necklace?
你不该把它给我
You never should have given it to me.
我不是守护者 我根本看不到凤凰
I am no Guardian. I can't even see the Phoenix.
没事的 汤姆 一切都会好起来的
It's okay, Tom. Everything's going to be okay.
给我吧现在
I'll take it now.
那不是她
It's not her!
不
No!
离她远点
Leave her alone!
哦 看看 有人长本事了
Oh, look at you. Somebody's been learning.
而你 真是忘恩负义
And you. So ungrateful.
你让鹿妈妈失望了
You disappoint your Mama Loo.
是吗? 你真是个糟糕的妈妈
Yeah? You were a terrible mom!
- 你的厨艺也很烂  - 我们走
- And your cooking sucked!  - Let's go!
- 走, 走, 走  - 好的
- Go, go, go!  - Okay!
谢谢你, 托马斯
Thank you, Thomas.
真不敢相信他又跑了
I can't believe he did this again.
他为什么总是要逃避我?
Why does he keep running away from me?
哦, 是吗? 还是你一直在把他推开?
Oh, does he? Or do you keep pushing him away? Hmm?
- 这绝对不是真的  - 是吗?
- That's not true at all.  - Oh, really?
- 我已经受够了...  - 哈
- I've had about enough of...  - Ha!
猫的典型行为
Typical cat behavior.
什么? 我才不
What? I don't...
极度独立? 领地意识极强?
Fiercely independent? Territorial?
我还应该提到过度梳妆吗?
Should I even mention the excessive grooming?
嘿, 猫是不会在你叫它的时候来找你的
Hey. A cat won't come to you when you call them.
他们希望一切都按照自己的节奏来, 在他们自己觉得合适的时候
They want everything on their own terms, when it suits them,
即使是对他们真正关心的人
even with the people they truly care about.
我说错了吗?
Am I wrong?
没错
No.
我疏远了他们
I pushed them all away.
汤姆 生肖们 你可能是最多的
Tom, the Zodiac, you probably the most.
但你就不会离开我, 龙
But you wouldn't leave me, Dragon.
为什么会这样?
Why is that?
我想我就是个猫奴
I guess I'm just a cat person.
汤姆
Tom!
我把它弄丢了
I lost it.
凤凰石在鹿手里
Loo has the Phoenix.
我想如果我回到我们的家
I thought maybe if I went back to our house,
我就能理解她为什么没告诉我
I could understand why she didn't tell me,
我刚刚找到了这个
and I just found this.
哇哦 你还是个婴儿的时候 我就把这个给你了
Wow. I gave that to you when you were just a baby.
是吗?
You did?
我一直都在守护着你的一生
I've been watching over you your whole life.
自从那晚在桥上以后
Ever since that night on the bridge.
我们知道鹿会回来的
We knew Loo would be back.
所以我和你奶奶决定把你藏起来, 保护我们的血脉
So your grandma and I decided to hide you, to protect the bloodline.
很有效...
And it worked...
直到我把那孩子扔上天花板?
Until I threw that kid into the ceiling?
- 并取下了保护符  - 但你并不知情
- And pulled down the protective charms.  - But you didn't know.
我让鹿拿走了凤凰石
I let Loo take the Phoenix.
我的错
That's on me.
对不起, 我不是最好的导师
I'm sorry I wasn't the best mentor.
但千年之后, 我终于意识到
But what I'm finally realizing after a thousand years
什么才是最重要的
is what matters most,
那就是摆脱一切勇敢前行
and that's how you move forward.
我不知道我是不是能成为那个你们最需要的人
I don't know if I can be who you need me to be.
你已经是了
You already are.
就在你的血脉里
It's in your blood.
你是上千代守护者的后裔, 汤姆
You come from a thousand generations of Guardians, Tom.
你奶奶给了你项链
Your grandma gave you the necklace.
她相信你
She believed in you.
好的
All right.
我们怎么找到鹿?
How do we find Loo?
我们去找凤凰
We find the Phoenix.
鹿在等待日落, 那时能量会达到顶峰
Loo's waiting for sundown, when the energy is at its peak.
好了, 伸出手去感应凤凰吧
All right, reach out and find that Phoenix.
太吵了
It's too much.
汤姆, 集中注意力
Tom, focus.
我做不到 我不行
I can't. I'm losing it.
深呼吸 找些能依靠的 能让自己安定下来的东西
Just breathe. Find something to hold on to, something to anchor yourself.
没事的 你没事的
It's okay. You're okay.
鹿!
Loo!
托马斯, 和你奶奶一个样
Thomas, just like your grandmother.
顽抗到底
Persistent to the end.
哇哦
Whoa!
嘿!
Hey!
满脸的猴爪印
Face full of monkey paw!
去把这些畜牲们撕成碎片
Tear the animals apart.
淘气, 淘气的 妖怪
Naughty, naughty yaoguai!
哦, 拿你的手当饺子!
Oh, now your hand is a dumpling!
介意借我用一下吗?
Mind if I borrow this?
再见 谢谢!
Bye. Thanks!
是啊
Yeah!
护身咒
Protection spell!
护身咒?
Protection spell?
如果那会你在那里保护你的奶奶就好了
If only you were there to protect your grandmother.
怪物
Monster!
坚持住
Hang on!
不
No!
阿汤
Ah Tom.
阿嫲
Ah Ma.
汤姆
Tom!
不
No!
虎
Hu!
我好像就是要不停地夺走
I just can't seem to stop taking away
所有你关心的人
all the people you care about.
可怜的托马斯
Poor Thomas.
你知道那晚在桥上我为什么没杀你吗?
Do you know why I didn't kill you that night on the bridge?
就在那时, 我从你的眼中看出来
Even then, I saw it in your eyes.
你毫无威胁, 因为你不是守护者
You were no threat, because you were no Guardian.
不 那只是另一个谎言 是虎那天晚上救了我
No, that's just another lie. Hu saved me that night.
现在你的老虎还救得了你吗
Well, where's your tiger now?
鹿的伞
Hey! Loo's umbrella!
快 抓住它 我们得解救其他生肖
Quick, grab it! We gotta free the other Zodiacs!
这太疯狂了 太疯狂了
This is crazy! This is crazy!
我来 我来
I got it. I got it.
不
No!
我拿到了 在怪物堆里追逐一把邪恶的伞
I got it! Chasing an evil umbrella through a swarm of monsters.
这样很好!
This is fine!
纳奥米 帮个小忙
Naomi! A little help here.
你就是这样帮忙的?
This is how you help?
你不知道我等这一刻等了多久
You have no idea how long I've waited for this moment.
借助凤凰的力量, 我可以重塑世界
With the power of the Phoenix, I can remake the world
消灭人类
without humans,
我给你留了个前排座位
and I've saved you a front-row seat.
还等什么 娜奥米
Anytime, Naomi!
放了我的朋友们, 你这蠢伞!
Let my friends go, you stupid umbrella!
快点出来 快点出来
好了 生肖们 我们要保护守护者 一起上
All right, Zodiacs. We got a Guardian to protect! Together.
我们上吧
Let's do this!
汤姆?
Tom?
不 不
No. No!
看看 托马斯 不是很漂亮吗?
Look at it, Thomas. Isn't it beautiful?
我们来了, 孩子
We're coming, kid!
你跑得太慢了, 老虎
Way ahead of you, Tiger!
驾
Giddyap!
我会让你们知道谁是老大!
I'll show you who's in charge!
加农炮弹
Cannonball!
再扔给我一个
Throw me another one!
好的, 没错
Yeah, that's right.
你能听到吗?
Can you hear that?
虎! 十二生肖上场
Hu! Yeah! Zodiac up!
哇哦
Whoa.
Whoa!
吃我一脚
Monkey foot!
嗨呀
Hi-yah!
山羊
Goat!
你们来得太晚了
You're too late!
够了
Enough!
现在, 我要一劳永逸了结这一切
Now I end this once and for all.
来吧 托马斯
Come, Thomas.
你可以在战斗中去死
You can die fighting
就像你的奶奶一样
just like your grandmother did.
我们不需要战斗
We don't need to fight.
你以为你在干什么, 孩子?
What do you think you're doing, boy?
我们不需要这些
We don't need these.
我们需要这个
We need this.
还有这个
And this.
我现在明白了, 阿嫲
I understand now, Ah Ma.
来吧 孩子 跟我打
Come, boy. Fight me.
汤姆
Tom.
我看到了凤凰
I see the Phoenix.
不
No!
嘘 嘿
Shh. Hey.
没关系
It's okay.
我是来保护你的
I'm here to protect you.
在你手中, 凤凰摧毁一切!
In your hands, the Phoenix destroys!
不
No!
但在对的人手中...
But in the right hands...
汤姆 醒醒
Tom! Wake up!
汤姆, 你听到了吗?
Tom, do you hear me?
伙计们, 他没呼吸了
Guys, he's not breathing.
汤姆?
Tom?
来吧, 别离开我们, 伙计
Come on, stay with us, buddy.
不 不
No. No!
我们不能让他死
We just can't let him die.
女娲
Nu Kua?
来吧
Do it.
好吧, 快!
Okay, quick!
这需要我们所有人的一起协作
It's gonna take all of us together.
谢谢你们, 我的朋友们
Thank you, my friends.
女皇 我寻求您的帮助!
Empress! I seek your help!
女皇
Empress!
我的徒弟, 他为了拯救凡人牺牲了自己
My apprentice, he sacrificed himself to save the mortals.
这孩子已经无法治愈了
The boy is beyond healing.
但还没到无可挽救的地步
But not beyond saving.
往下看 老虎告诉我 你看到了什么?
Look down, Tiger. Tell me, what do you see?
水 海洋
Water. An ocean.
泪海, 是所有灵魂最后归宿的地方
The Sea of Tears, where all souls go at the end.
拿我的灵魂来换吧
Take mine instead.
把我们的灵魂融合在一起, 就像李太太为我做的那样!
Merge our souls as Mrs. Lee did for me!
你可能会和他一起死
You could die along with him.
我不怕
I'm not afraid.
我明白了
I see that.
老虎, 你向来都不怕死
Your spirit has never been subtle, Tiger.
跟我一起念
Repeat these words.
"以我之血, 你我相合"
"With my blood, I join you."
以我之血, 你我相合
With my blood, I join you.
"以我之息, 你我相连"
"With my breath, I bind you."
以我之息, 你我相连
With my breath, I bind you.
嘿, 孩子
Hey, kid.
你怎么了?
What happened to you?
谁能知道呢?
What do you know?
原来老虎的性格也是改变的!
I guess a tiger can change his stripes!
好极了 现在我永远也忘不掉这句了
Great. Now I'm gonna be hearing that one forever.
所以, 你舍不得我死, 是吧?
So you couldn't let me die, huh?
是啊, 我们就不要大惊小怪了
Yeah, let's not make some big fuss about it.
托马斯·李
Thomas Lee,
我们封你为守护者
we name you Guardian.
干得漂亮 祝贺你
Nice work. Congratulations.
你会做得很好的, 孩子, 只要你乖乖听我的
You're gonna do great, kid, the sooner you listen to everything that I say.
他们长得真快
They grow up so fast.
他是你的未婚夫吗?
Is he your fiancé?
什么? 不, 我们是高中生
What? No. We're in high school.
现在还不算太晚
It's not too late.
我还有一件东西要给你
There's just one more thing I have for you.
神圣的礼物
A sacred gift.
好吧 是空的
Uh, cool. It's empty.
什么?
What?
嗯, 好吧, 好吧
Hmm, okay, okay.
这就是一个隐喻, 不是吗?
It's like a metaphor, isn't it?
西德
Sid.
什么? 哦 当然 啥都怪老鼠 我就知道
What? Oh, sure, blame the rat. I see how it is.
我也不知道这是哪来的
I have no idea how it got there.
我给你打了一把我店里的钥匙
I-I-I made you a key to my shop.
这就是你的神圣礼物?
That's your sacred gift?
我估计你还有更多要训练的 你会需要地方住的
I figured you've got more training to do and you're gonna need somewhere to stay,
所以, 如果你, 我不知道, 把那当作你的....
so maybe it would make sense if you, I don't know, consider it your...
家?
Home?
是的, 如果你乐意的话
Yeah. I mean, if you want.
我身上确实有你的一部分灵魂
Well, I do have a piece of your soul in me,
所以, 我想这大概让我们成了一家人
so I guess that kind of makes us family.
我就知道我们需要纸巾 你个大软猫
Okay, I knew we were gonna need tissues. You big softy.
我为你感到骄傲, 虎
I'm proud of you, Hu.
都是被现在的那些香给薰的
It's whatever they're putting in the incense these days.
是啊 好借口
Yeah. Good cover.
我知道你很老套
I get that you're, like, old-school,
但有情绪也没关系
but it's okay to have emotions.
学徒, 你会看到很多情绪的
You're about to see some emotions, apprentice.
学徒? 守护者
Apprentice? Guardian.
你还有很多东西要学
You've still got a lot to learn.
对不起
I'm sorry.
是你抓住了真正的凤凰, 拯救了世界吗?
Were you the one who grabbed the actual Phoenix and saved the world?
- 我可不这么认为  - 是我一次又一次地救了你这个可怜虫
- I don't think so!  - I'm the one who saved your sorry butt over and over.
我叫你帮忙了吗? 我自己都搞定了
Did I ask for your help? I had it back there.
老虎
的学徒
SUBTiTLE: DEX𝟕ER
"虎视眈眈"? 开什么玩笑
"Eye of the Tiger"? You gotta be kidding me.
这是经典歌曲
It's a classic.
- 这不是重点  - 什么重点?
- That's not the point.  - What?
- 你是一只老虎  - 那又怎样?
- You're a tiger.  - So what?
你真的不明白这是怎么...
Are you really not understanding how this is...
- 这首歌就是为我而写的  - 让我...
- This song is written for me.  - Let me just...
别碰那个 让我听听我的音乐
Do not touch that. Just let me play my music.
哦, 是的
Oh, yeah.
哦 是的 这是我的菜
Oh, yeah. That's my jam.
你真的需要多出去走走
You really need to get out more.
你需要更多的培训
And you need more training.
哇哦
Whoa!
好的, 等等
Okay, hold on!
虎太喜欢这样了
Hu enjoys this far too much.
赌五块钱, 这孩子赢了
Five bucks the kid aces it.
赌就赌
You're on.
仅供参考, 我没钱
Just FYI, I don't have money.
哇哦, 你在干什么?
Whoa. Hey, what are you doing?
哇哦 停下 不 等等 不
Whoa! Stop! No! Wait! Hey. No. No.
酷毙了
Cool.
好吧, 我们不会共用一个猫砂盆的
Okay, we're not sharing the same litter box.
Rising up Back on the street,
Rising up Back on the street
Did my time, took my chances
Fly away Now I'm back on my feet
And that keeps me dancing
So many times It can happen too fast
Change your passion For glory
Don't lose your grip
On the dreams of your past
You gotta tell them To instruct me
It's the eye of the tiger
It's the thrill of the fight
Moving to the pulse Of our rivals
If they come to me
In the middle of the night
I'll be watching With all of the eye
Of the tiger
Ooh-ooh-ooh
Fly high I feel like
I'm on top Of the world
In the sky, yeah
Feel like I'm on top Of the world
Can't deny I feel like
I'm on top of the world
Fly high I feel like
I'm on top Of the world
In the sky, yeah Feel like
Can't deny I feel like
I'm on top of the world
I survive 'cause I
Came from the bottom
Now I'm on the mountaintop
Came from struggle One that caught me
Now, like rock 'n' roll I rock it
This is all I got
I don't need to be specific
Want the stars on
my spaceship Feeling futuristic, ah
I like nice things They like me too
I dream so sweet I feel so new
It's what I say When I want you
Fly high I feel like
I'm on top Of the world
In the sky, yeah Feel like
Can't deny I feel like
I'm on top of the world
I survive 'cause I feel Like
I don't really care
What they say about me
Leave 'em like the seas I'll whoa, whoa
I don't really care
What they say about me
Leave 'em like the seas I'll
Feel like I'm on top of the world